<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://KiarashS.github.io/reader2/index.html</id>
    <title>My RSS Reader 2::Kiarash Soleimanzadeh</title>
    <updated>2024-11-08T01:43:16.433Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://KiarashS.github.io/reader2/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://KiarashS.github.io/reader2/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Your Own RAG Chatbot with JavaScript!]]></title>
        <id>672cebbcd4b84c7df59edd79</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-your-own-rag-chatbot-with-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-07T16:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generative AI is rapidly evolving, and with it comes the ability to create powerful applications like chatbots that go beyond static knowledge. Imagine building a chatbot that isn’t limited by outdated training data or predefined responses but can fe...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn the Foundations of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence]]></title>
        <id>672cea4be28457c681419f0d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-the-foundations-of-machine-learning-and-artificial-intelligence/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-07T16:26:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you know, machine learning and artificial intelligence (AI) are transforming the world around us. Mastering these tools can open doors to exciting career opportunities. We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will t...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Set Up Automated GitHub Workflows for Your Python and React Applications]]></title>
        <id>672cdb23b9bae98eb2d22c19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-set-up-automated-github-workflows-for-python-react-apps/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-07T15:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automating workflows is an essential step in helping you maintain code quality in your applications – especially when working on both frontend and backend code in a single repository. In this guide, we’ll walk through setting up automated GitHub work...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preston Osoro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working With DTO Auto Translators -- Mapperly]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.peterritchie.com/posts/working-with-dto-auto-translators--mapperly</id>
        <link href="http://blog.peterritchie.com/posts/working-with-dto-auto-translators--mapperly"/>
        <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="../assets/mapping-translation.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Complicated translation"></p>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Ritchie's Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use LangChain and GPT to Analyze Multiple Documents]]></title>
        <id>672b941f0c32c8c8cd6159a9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-langchain-and-gpt-to-analyze-multiple-documents/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-06T16:06:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past year or so, the developer universe has exploded with ingenious new tools, applications, and processes for working with large language models and generative AI. One particularly versatile example is the LangChain project. The overall goa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Clinton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popping Comments With CSS Anchor Positioning and View-Driven Animations]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382247</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/popping-comments-with-css-anchor-positioning-and-view-driven-animations/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-06T15:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The State of CSS 2024 survey wrapped up and the results are interesting, as always. Even though each section is worth analyzing, we are usually most hyped about the section on the most used CSS features. And if you …
Popping Comments With CSS Anchor Positioning and View-Driven Animations originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Diego Rodríguez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fluid Everything Else]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382107</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/fluid-everything-else/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T20:49:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We can apply the concept of fluid typography to almost anything. This way we can have a layout that fluidly changes with the size of its parent container. Few users will ever see the transition, but they will all appreciate the results. Honestly, they will.
Fluid Everything Else originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Hubbard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Write Clean Code – Tips for Developers with Examples]]></title>
        <id>672a51c02bb94277a075a484</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-write-clean-code-tips-for-developers/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T17:11:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine a messy room with clothes, books, and other items scattered everywhere. Finding something in that room would be tough, right? Now, think about writing messy code – it’s just as confusing, if not more! On the other hand, clean code is like an ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Programming with Shahan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Integrate Tailwind with Django – With Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>672a2317dd9236b285ebb527</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-integrate-tailwind-with-django/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T13:52:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In modern web development, choosing the right technology is crucial because it impacts both the process and outcome of your projects. Using Django as a backend framework and Tailwind CSS as a utility-first CSS framework offers an efficient way to cre...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhijeet Dave</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Launch an EC2 Instance and Set Up a Web Server Using HTTPD]]></title>
        <id>672a1e5f52317a5d102c0dd9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-launch-an-ec2-instance-and-a-web-server-using-httpd/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T13:32:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey there! Have you ever thought about creating your own web server on the cloud? Well, you’re in for a treat because in this article, we’re going to explore how you can launch an EC2 instance and use HTTPD to host a simple web server. Don’t worry – ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kedar Makode</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[API CRUD Course in Spanish – Learn Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and Authentication]]></title>
        <id>672a09ff678d23ad0f6618bd</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/api-crud-course-in-spanish-learn-nodejs-express-mongodb-and-authentication/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T12:05:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CRUD operations are the foundation of back-end web development. CRUD stands for Create, Read, Update, and Delete. They are essential operations for modern web development because they are used to manage data in most web applications. We just publishe...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Estefania Cassingena Navone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Optimizing Your Lighthouse Score Is Not Enough For A Fast Website]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/11/why-optimizing-lighthouse-score-not-enough-fast-website/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/11/why-optimizing-lighthouse-score-not-enough-fast-website/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling good with your Lighthouse score of 100%? You should! But you should also know that you’re only looking at part of the performance picture. Learn how Lighthouse scores are measured differently than other tools, the impact that has on measuring performance metrics, and why you need real-user monitoring for a complete picture.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Geoff Graham)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Fuzz Test Golang HTTP Services]]></title>
        <id>672941e6066de072ede39685</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-fuzz-test-golang-http-services/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-04T21:51:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a developer, you can’t always envision all of the possible inputs your programs or functions might receive. Even though you can define the major edge cases, you still can’t predict how your program will behave in the case of some weird unexpected ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Pliutau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Become an Open Source Master]]></title>
        <id>67293d27f76256c5c96d08f9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/become-an-open-source-master/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-04T21:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Open-source software has transformed the tech industry, creating powerful opportunities for learning, growth, and collaboration. By contributing to open-source projects, you can build essential coding skills, gain real-world experience, and make mean...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web-Slinger.css: Like Wow.js But With CSS-y Scroll Animations]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382156</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/web-slinger-css-like-wow-js-but-with-css-y-scroll-animations/"/>
        <updated>2024-11-01T14:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can we recreate a JavaScript library for scrolling animations with a modern CSS approach using CSS Scroll-Driven Animations? Yes. Yes, we can.
Web-Slinger.css: Like Wow.js But With CSS-y Scroll Animations originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lee Meyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top Cybersecurity Certifications You Should Know About as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>6723aaab6ac0ce6c240da454</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/top-cybersecurity-certifications-for-devs/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-31T16:04:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cybersecurity remains one of the fastest-growing fields today, and for a good reason. The need for skilled cyber defenders grows as our lives and businesses go ever more digital. A cybersecurity certification can help you boost your skills and demons...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manish Shivanandhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Generative AI for Developers]]></title>
        <id>6723a4a233e12497593c1eae</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-generative-ai-for-developers/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-31T15:39:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generative AI is reshaping the landscape of artificial intelligence, allowing machines to create text, images, audio, and even answer questions in natural language. But understanding the entire end-to-end process can be complex without structured gui...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ingredients For A Cozy November (2024 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-november-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-november-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-31T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[November is just around the corner and that means: It’s time for some new desktop wallpapers! Created with love by the community for the community, they are available in versions with and without a calendar. Enjoy!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Write Extension Methods in C#]]></title>
        <id>6722f316b717c1a9c6f35b34</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-write-extension-methods-in-csharp/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-31T03:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Extension methods are a fundamental part of C# and Object Oriented Programming (OOP). Extension methods in C# allow you to "extend" existing types, including classes, interfaces, or structs, without modifying their original code. This is particularly...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grant Riordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Remove All Saved Posts from Facebook Using JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>67228665c48a2523d1dedb0a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/remove-all-saved-posts-from-facebook-using-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-30T19:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're an avid Facebook user, you've probably saved countless posts, videos, and links to revisit later. But sometimes, these saved posts accumulate and become overwhelming. You may decide to un-save them all at once rather than manually uncheckin...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Md. Fahim Bin Amin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of CSS 2024 Results]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382144</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/state-of-css-2024-results/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-30T16:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The results from this year's survey are fairly fresh off the presses. We took a little time to sit with them and jot down some things we noticed and found interesting.
State of CSS 2024 Results originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Developer Tools to Debug JavaScript in the Browser]]></title>
        <id>67224a271058ad4196106527</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-developer-tools-to-debug-javascript-in-the-browser/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-30T15:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The console object is the number one go-to for developers when working with buggy JavaScript code. But if you still rely heavily on the console object alone to debug your JavaScript, then you're missing out on some amazing browser developer tools fea...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kolade Chris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing For Gen Z: Expectations And UX Guidelines]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/designing-for-gen-z/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/designing-for-gen-z/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are many myths revolving around Gen Z and how they use tech. Time to take a look at actual behavior patterns that go beyond heavy use of social media. Part of [Smart Interface Design Patterns](https://smart-interface-design-patterns.com) by yours truly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are Smart Pointers in Rust? Explained with Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>6721aeb8d9c3d37db41183a6</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/smart-pointers-in-rust-with-code-examples/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-30T03:57:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smart pointers are data structures that act like pointers but contain extra information and have functionalities that make them excel over regular pointers in certain situations. So what are regular pointers? Regular pointers (just called “pointers”)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oduah Chigozie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Merge Multiple Google Docs into One Using Apps Script or the Google Docs API]]></title>
        <id>672103feae01d783da13018b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/merge-multiple-google-docs-with-apps-script-or-google-docs-api/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-29T15:49:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merging multiple Google Docs into a single document is often essential for compiling reports, gathering information from various sources, or creating unified documents for presentations or sharing. By combining multiple files into one, users can keep...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Aruchamy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve and and Restructure Your Codebase with AI Tools & Version Control]]></title>
        <id>6720f7fb2e452955f9433899</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-and-restructure-codebase-with-ai-tools/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-29T14:58:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A codebase can become messy and hard to manage over time. This happens because of quick fixes, outdated features, or just not enough time to clean things up. When code becomes difficult to read or change, it slows down progress and can even cause bug...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oluwadamisi Samuel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tooltip Best Practices]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382082</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/tooltip-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-29T14:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are tooltips, exactly? There's two kinds and the one you use has implications on the user experience, as Zell illustrates in this explainer on best practices.
Tooltip Best Practices originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zell Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools You Can Use for Open Source Intelligence (OSINT) Gathering]]></title>
        <id>671fdfa416219baf5b89e52a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/tools-for-open-source-intelligence-gathering/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-28T19:01:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the world of Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT). OSINT is all about gathering public information from various online sources. OSINT can come from social media, websites, search engines, and even public databases. You’d be surprised at how mu...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manish Shivanandhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[freeCodeCamp Turns 10 + Major Certification Updates]]></title>
        <id>671fc26234113ef3b02f6bf3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/freecodecamp-turns-10-major-curriculum-updates/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-28T16:57:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[10 years ago today I sat down in the closet of my San Francisco apartment and coded the first few hundred lines of freeCodeCamp. I didn't know it at the time, but fCC would quickly grow into a global community of busy adults learning to code togethe...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quincy Larson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Message Queues Help Make Distributed Systems More Reliable]]></title>
        <id>671f94819cd90a859ae00b55</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-message-queues-make-distributed-systems-more-reliable/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-28T13:41:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reliable systems consistently perform their intended functions under various conditions while minimizing downtime and failures. As internet users, we tend to take for granted that the systems that we use daily will operate reliably. In this article, ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anant Chowdhary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Dorking: How to Find Hidden Information on the Web]]></title>
        <id>671bf3858ac006ad747be97f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/google-dorking-how-to-find-hidden-information-on-the-web/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T19:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s learn how to find hidden information online by using advanced search operators on Google. The internet holds vast amounts of information. Much of this information is accessible through Google. But did you know you can use Google in ways beyond ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manish Shivanandhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy Your Project On Vercel With A Custom Domain]]></title>
        <id>671bf3148df28644ca9012f9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-your-project-on-vercel/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T19:35:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever built a project but found it difficult to make it live on the internet? Well, worry no more because this article will help you do that. In this article, I will introduce you to one of the fastest and easiest deployment platforms for bri...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okoro Emmanuel Nzube</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[freeCodeCamp's Top Open Source Contributors of 2024]]></title>
        <id>671be68e68f1df3481f20947</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/freecodecamps-top-open-source-contributors-of-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T18:42:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2024 has been an extremely productive year for the freeCodeCamp community. We’ve built up an incredible amount of momentum toward our missioncreating open learning resources for everyone. Over the past 12 months, the freeCodeCamp community has: Merg...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quincy Larson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Write Cleaner JavaScript Code with The Ternary Operator]]></title>
        <id>671bc601bf239575d6efca0c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/write-cleaner-javascript-code-with-the-ternary-operator/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T16:23:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're coding in JavaScript, handling decisions through conditional statements is one of the core tasks you'll frequently encounter. One of the most commonly used methods for this is the ternary operator. But what exactly is it, and when should ...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oluwadamisi Samuel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Stealing Cars to Self-Taught Software Engineer with Dorian Develops [Podcast #147]]]></title>
        <id>671bb68ab1de10b671182954</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/from-stealing-cars-to-self-taught-software-engineer-dorian-develops-podcast-147/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T15:17:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On this week's episode of the podcast, I interview Dorian Develops. He's a software engineer and prolific YouTube creator. Dorian grew up in the Little Havana neighborhood of Miami. He's the child of a single mother that arrived as a refugee from Cub...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quincy Larson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Come to the light-dark() Side]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382039</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/come-to-the-light-dark-side/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T14:08:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’d be forgiven for thinking coding up both a dark and a light mode at once is a lot of work. You have to remember @media queries based on prefers-color-scheme as well as extra complications that arise when letting visitors …
Come to the light-dark() Side originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Joy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Left Half and Right Half Layout – Many Different Ways]]></title>
        <id>http://css-tricks.com/?p=198099</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/left-and-right/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T11:51:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A whole bunch of years ago, we posted on this idea here on CSS-Tricks. We figured it was time to update that and do the subject justice.
Imagine a scenario where you need to split a layout in half. Content …
Left Half and Right Half Layout – Many Different Ways originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Object-Oriented Programming in Python – Key OOP Concepts and Interview Questions for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>671aeea7c5f85f75b4b243e8</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/object-oriented-programming-in-python-interview-questions/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-25T01:04:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OOP is a crucial concept that every developer should grasp, especially when getting ready for job interviews. It helps you organize code into modular and reusable sections, which simplifies the development, maintenance, and scaling of software applic...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Casmir Onyekani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Sql Server on Windows ARM]]></title>
        <id>4648676_202410242159</id>
        <link href="https://weblog.west-wind.com/posts/2024/Oct/24/Using-Sql-Server-on-Windows-ARM"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T21:59:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently picked up a Windows ARM device in the form of a Samsung Galaxy Book 4 with a SnapDragon X Elite chip. Best Buy had a sale going for $799 at the time, and so I 'snapped' one up.
I've been wanting to get my hands on an ARM machine to check how some of my Windows applications run on an ARM device and how well these machines work as mainline Windows machine. While I didn't intend this to be my main machine, from testing and using it as a portable machine away from my big laptop, the verdict is in: Most things work very well without any changes.



Everything works - except SQL Server!
When I picked this machine up and started installing my typical developer and productivity workload on it, I was expecting a lot of stuff to not work or work badly through emulation.
Just about everyth…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rick Strahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Implement Fine-Grained Authorization in Java and SpringBoot]]></title>
        <id>671a85db0db570158155ec00</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/fine-grained-authorization-in-java-and-springboot/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T17:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Securing your application goes beyond simply granting or denying access at the surface level. As a developer, you need to implement fine-grained authorization (FGA) to manage permissions at a more detailed, granular level. FGA allows you to set up de...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankur Tyagi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code a Full Stack AI-Powered Email SaaS]]></title>
        <id>671a6769ad3ef266b980f1f7</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/code-a-full-stack-ai-powered-email-saas/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T15:27:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you ready to dive into the world of full-stack web development and AI-powered applications? This comprehensive tutorial takes you through the exciting process of building and deploying an intelligent, fully-featured email client from scratch. Usi...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare For and Pass the Google Cloud Digital Leader Certification Exam]]></title>
        <id>671a661b1687492df2d18436</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/prepare-for-and-pass-the-google-cloud-digital-leader-certification-exam/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T15:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've just released a comprehensive course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel to help you prepare for the Google Cloud Digital Leader certification exam – and it's completely free. This in-depth course, created by cloud expert Andrew Brown, is d...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Your Own Private Hacking Lab with VirtualBox]]></title>
        <id>671a63a2c56e050e75cb0298</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-private-hacking-lab-with-virtualbox/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T15:11:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ethical hacking involves testing and finding vulnerabilities in systems. But doing this on live networks or public servers can lead to accidental damage. Setting up a virtual lab for hacking is a great way to sharpen your skills in a safe environment...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manish Shivanandhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can use text-wrap: balance; on icons]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382065</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/you-can-use-text-wrap-balance-on-icons/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T14:05:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terence Eden on using text-wrap: balance for more than headings:
But the name is, I think, slightly misleading. It doesn’t only work on text. It will work on any content. For example – I have a row of icons at 
…
You can use text-wrap: balance; on icons originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naming things: Actions]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.peterritchie.com/posts/naming-things--generic-actions</id>
        <link href="http://blog.peterritchie.com/posts/naming-things--generic-actions"/>
        <updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="../assets/overwhelming-possibilities.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Overwhelming Possibilities"></p>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Ritchie's Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clarifying the Relationship Between Popovers and Dialogs]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=382008</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/clarifying-the-relationship-between-popovers-and-dialogs/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-23T13:20:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The difference between Popovers (i.e., the popover attribute) and Dialogs (i.e., both the <dialog element and the dialog accessible role) is incredibly confusing — so much that many articles (like this, this, and this) have tried to …
Clarifying the Relationship Between Popovers and Dialogs originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zell Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clamp it! VS Code extension]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381992</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/clamp-it-vs-code-extension/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-23T13:15:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a lot of math behind fluid typography. CSS does make the math a lot easier these days, but even if you’re comfortable with that, writing the full declaration can be verbose and tough to remember. I know I often …
Clamp it! VS Code extension originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unleash the Power of Scroll-Driven Animations]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/unleash-the-power-of-scroll-driven-animations/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-21T13:50:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m utterly behind in learning about scroll-driven animations apart from the “reading progress bar” experiments all over CodePen. Well, I’m not exactly “green” on the topic; we’ve published a handful of articles on it including this neat-o one by Lee …
Unleash the Power of Scroll-Driven Animations originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combining forces, GSAP & Webflow!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381832</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/combining-forces-gsap-webflow/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-18T13:09:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change can certainly be scary whenever a beloved, independent software library becomes a part of a larger organization. I’m feeling a bit more excitement than concern this time around, though.
If you haven’t heard, GSAP (GreenSock Animation Platform) is teaming …
Combining forces, GSAP & Webflow! originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Trimble</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastering theme.json: You might not need CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381882</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/mastering-theme-json-you-might-not-need-css/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-18T11:36:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I totally get the goal here: make CSS more modular and scalable in WordPress. Put all your global WordPress theme styles in a single file, including variations. JSON offers a nicely structured syntax that’s easily consumable by JavaScript, thereby allowing …
Mastering theme.json: You might not need CSS originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solving Background Overflow With Inherited Border Radii]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381763</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/preventing-child-background-overflow-with-inherited-border-radii/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-17T15:24:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the interesting (but annoying) things about CSS is the background of children’s elements can bleed out of the border radius of the parent element. Here’s an example of a card with an inner element. If the inner element …
Solving Background Overflow With Inherited Border Radii originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zell Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS min() All The Things]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/css-min-all-the-things/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/css-min-all-the-things/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Victor Ayomipo experiments with the CSS `min()` function, exploring its flexibility with different units to determine if it is the be-all, end-all for responsiveness. Discover the cautions he highlights against dogmatic approaches to web design based on his findings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Victor Ayomipo)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Close, Exit, Cancel: How to End User Interactions Well]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381817</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/close-exit-cancel-how-to-end-user-interactions-well/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:12:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What’s in a word? Actions. In the realm of user interfaces, a word is construed as the telltale of a control’s action. Sometimes it points us in the correct direction, and sometimes it leads us astray. We talk a lot …
Close, Exit, Cancel: How to End User Interactions Well originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Here! How To Measure UX &amp; Design Impact, With Vitaly Friedman]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/new-video-course-how-to-measure-ux-design-impact/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/new-video-course-how-to-measure-ux-design-impact/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design decisions shouldn’t be a matter of personal preference. We can use reliable design KPIs and UX metrics to guide and shape our design work and measure its impact on business. Meet How To Measure UX and Design Impact, our new video course that helps with just that.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Tricks That Use Only One Gradient]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381773</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-tricks-that-use-only-one-gradient/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-11T21:48:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS gradients have been so long that there’s no need to rehash what they are and how to use them. You have surely encountered them at some point in your front-end journey, and if you follow me, you also …
CSS Tricks That Use Only One Gradient originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Multimodal AI Models For Your Applications (Part 3)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/using-multimodal-ai-models-applications-part3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2024/10/using-multimodal-ai-models-applications-part3/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this third part of the series, you are looking at two models that handle all three modalities — text, images or videos, and audio — without needing a second model for text-to-speech or speech recognition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Joas Pambou)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WPGraphQL Becomes a Canonical Plugin: My Move to Automattic]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381752</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wpgraphql-becomes-a-canonical-plugin-my-move-to-automattic/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-10T14:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s always a gas when a good person doing good work gets a good deal. In this case, Jason’s viral WPGraphQL plugin has not only become a canonical WordPress plugin, but creator Jason Bahl is joining Automattic as well.
I’m …
WPGraphQL Becomes a Canonical Plugin: My Move to Automattic originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024: More CSS At-Rules Than the Past Decade Combined]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381678</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2024-more-css-at-rules-than-the-past-decade-combined/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-09T14:10:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More times than I can count, while writing, I get myself into random but interesting topics with little relation to the original post. In the end, I have to make the simple but painful choice of deleting or archiving hours …
2024: More CSS At-Rules Than the Past Decade Combined originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan Diego Rodríguez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Hour With Heydon Pickering]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=381729</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/smashing-hour-with-heydon-pickering/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-08T15:22:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I sat down with Heydon Pickering in the most recent episode of the Smashing Hour. Full transparency: I was nervous as heck. I’ve admired Heydon’s work for years, and even though we run in similar circles, this was our first …
Smashing Hour With Heydon Pickering originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>